scitation.org 2019-11-29

# 

Effective on: May 24, 2018

This Privacy Policy describes how AIP Publishing LLC (“ **AIP Publishing** ” or “ **we** ” or “ **us** ”) collects, uses, and discloses the information that we obtain through our Scitation website ([www.scitation.org](http://www.scitation.org/)), eSpectra website ([http://espectra.aip.org](http://espectra.aip.org/)), Peer X-Press websites, and the other online sites owned or operated by AIP Publishing that also link to this policy (the “ **Sites** ”), as well as information that we obtain offline. Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected through third-party websites or services that you access through the Sites.

Please review this Privacy Policy carefully. When you submit information to or through the Sites, you consent to the collection and processing of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. Unless otherwise stated here, this Privacy Policy is made part of our [Terms of Use](http://www.scitation.org/terms). We encourage you to review our Terms of Use, which contains important information about our liability to you when you use the Sites.

If you do not agree with any part of this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use, or, in the case of eSpectra, the User Agreement, then please do not use our Sites. Any specific privacy considerations in addition to this general policy will be noted where applicable.

**_Website-specific terms_** ** _  
_****_Information we collect_** ** _  
_****_The purpose in collecting Personal Information_** ** _  
_****_How Personal Information is shared_** ** _  
_****_Cookies and other data collection technologies_** ** _  
_****_Online advertising_** ** _  
_****_Your online choices_** ** _  
_****_Your access, rectification, deletion, and opt-out rights_** ** _  
_****_How we protect your Personal Information_** ** _  
_****_Data integrity and purpose limitation_** ** _  
_****_Records retention_** ** _  
_****_Your California rights_** ** _  
_****_User submissions_** ** _  
_****_Links and third-party websites_** ** _  
_****_Non-U.S. residents_** ** _  
_****_Notification of changes_** ** _  
_****_Contact information_** ** __**

**Website-specific terms**

**While the Privacy Policy describes AIP Publishing’s general privacy practices, the websites below have the following unique practices that diverge from the practices described elsewhere in the policy:**

**eSpectra:** If you use the eSpectra website, you accept the terms of this Privacy Policy, which is made part of the eSpectra User Agreement. If you have not done so already, please review our eSpectra User Agreement, which contains provisions specific to the eSpectra service. This Privacy Policy is expressly incorporated into the eSpectra User Agreement.

**Peer X-Press** : Peer X-Press (“PXP”) is AIP Publishing’s manuscript submission and peer review system. If you have registered for a PXP account, you will be asked to provide Personal Information, such as your name, ORCID number, email address, institutional affiliation, and country of residence. The primary purpose of gathering this information is to allow us to link a name and contact information to a user ID.

The Personal Information that you provide to us via the PXP site, regardless of which journal you register with, is maintained in the Peer X-Press database. A single account enables you to submit or review a manuscript for any AIP Publishing journal. It also allows for information to be shared by the editorial offices to facilitate efficient transfers of manuscripts. Member Society PXP account information, however, is maintained in separate databases and is not shared outside of the individual society.

If you are invited to review a manuscript, please be aware that although a reviewer's identity is never revealed to the author of the work itself, the report you provide, as well as your Personal Information, will be known to the editor and staff of any journal that considers the manuscript for publication. The same will hold true for an account that is created on your behalf when you are listed as a co-author for a manuscript submitted to an AIP Publishing or Member Society journal.

PXP is an online manuscript submission and peer review system, not a general website. While our Privacy Policy describes our general practices regarding the Personal Information obtained through our other websites, the Personal Information obtained through the PXP site is not shared with third parties other than our service providers to facilitate the peer review process, and, as stated above, with journal editorial offices and staff when manuscripts are transferred. We also do not market to PXP users without their express consent.

**Information we collect**

When you use our Sites, we collect Personal Information that helps us identify you as an individual, as well as Personal Information about your use of the Sites. The information that we collect and how we use it depends on how you use and access the Sites. We also collect Personal Information from you regarding the activities described on the Sites when you voluntarily send it to us outside of the Sites or offline. Such information shall be treated as Personal Information submitted through the Sites and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**_Personal Information_**

When you use our Sites, we collect Personal Information directly from you. “ **Personal Information** ” is any information that identifies an individual or relates to an identifiable individual, such as your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, or society membership details. We collect your Personal Information when you, for example, set up an account; register for a service, subscription, or alert; obtain access to certain content; sign up for a newsletter; submit a Comment or post on a blog or public message board; make a purchase; or send an inquiry to our customer service team.

We also collect your Personal Information from other organizations or individuals. For example, if you have registered with one of the Affiliated or Member Societies of the American Institute of Physics and access to our Sites is part of that registration, we will receive your Personal Information from that Member Society to set up your account and provide you with access. If you are provided with a subscription to our Sites through your employer or organization, we collect your Personal Information to set up your subscription. In addition, we collect your Personal Information from other individuals when, for example, an author suggests you as a reviewer for his or her paper or invites you to register for one of our Sites. In these cases, we will send you an email to notify you that you have been suggested as a reviewer and/or instructions for registering on our Sites.

We also provide an opportunity for you to share information with third-party social media services, such as by associating your social media account with our Sites. When you do so, these social media sites give us access to certain Personal Information that they store. When you associate your social media account with our Sites, you agree that we will collect, use, and store the information provided by that social media service as described in this Privacy Policy. When you visit our branded social media pages, such as on Twitter, LinkedIn, and Facebook, we collect the Personal Information you provide on those pages and treat that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

When you visit our Sites, Personal Information is automatically collected. For example, we use Google Analytics, which is a form of web measurement technology, to automatically track your interaction with our Sites and obtain insight into our website traffic and the effectiveness of our marketing. The type of Personal Information collected automatically includes but is not limited to your Internet domain and IP address, the URL address of the previous website you visited, the URL addresses of the webpages that you visited on our Sites, your browser and operating system type, whether you completed certain tasks or were successful in your online requests while on the Sites, and the date and time of your visit.

We will store and share this Personal Information among one or more of our internal databases and create an archival copy for record keeping and internal purposes. We also may enhance the data we collect with other information from third-party sources.

**The purpose in collecting Personal Information**

We primarily use the Personal Information we collect to improve your use of the Sites, to communicate with you about information that you request, and to help us do the following:

  * Operate the Sites effectively, deliver our products and services, and provide you with a more consistent and personalized experience when interacting with us.
  * Perform timely customer service and communicate important administrative and transactional announcements about the Sites or your account.
  * Create account efficiencies, such as a single customer record, and eliminate redundancies and duplication.
  * Enforce our Terms of Service and detect fraud or illegal activities.
  * Conduct surveys and questionnaires about our Sites and the services we offer.
  * Improve the overall security and functionality of the Sites to make your visit safer and more productive.
  * Provide you with editorial, marketing, and advertising information that we think is relevant to your areas of interest, including materials from our third-party business partners. We won’t share your Personal Information with these companies but will send you the information on their behalf.
  * Enable research and promote the innovation of our products and services.
  * Analyze and report on website usage.

**How Personal Information** **is shared**

We will share your Personal Information only for the reason(s) disclosed to you at the time that we collect it and in the following ways:

  * _At your direction:_ We will share your Personal Information with third parties when you tell us to. For example, if you fill out a form provided by one of our third-party sponsors or advertisers, we will provide that information to them for their own use.
  * _With related entities_ : We may disclose Personal Information to the American Institute of Physics (AIP Publishing’s parent), Affiliated or Member Societies of the American Institute of Physics, and subsidiaries or related companies owned by AIP Publishing. A list of related entities can be found at https://www.aip.org/member-societies.
  * _With our service providers:_ We share your information with our service providers that perform and offer services on our behalf. This allows us to enable specific services and functionality for which we have contracted or partnered, such as customizing our products or services, sending marketing and communications related to our business, payment processing, and improving our Sites. AIP Publishing is responsible for subsequent transfers to a third party acting as an agent on our behalf.
  * _For legal purposes:_ We will disclose your Personal Information to government authorities or third parties, as needed within our reasonable judgment, to identify fraud; to protect and enforce our rights or the rights of our customers or related entities; in response to a subpoena, regulation, or other legal process; and when required by law.
  * _During corporate changes:_ We will transfer your Personal Information in the event of a merger, sale, acquisition, or other change of ownership or control of our company (whether in whole or in part).

**Cookies and other data collection technologies**

AIP Publishing uses cookies, which are files that are placed on your computer when you first visit a webpage. Cookies allow you to move through the Sites more smoothly and enhance your user experience by making it more seamless. They also allow us to record information when you revisit our Sites, retain your customized preferences, and deliver advertisements to you that are tailored to your interests.

AIP Publishing also uses the following types of data collection technologies:

  * _Session cookies:_ Session cookies are designed so that once you close your browser, the cookie will simply terminate. They help you navigate the Sites by acting like placeholders or bookmarks to temporarily store information. Session cookies assist you in performing functions such as filling your shopping cart.
  * _Persistent cookies:_ Persistent cookies are permanent and remain on your computer after you terminate your session. Your ability to customize settings based on your own preferences is dependent on persistent cookies. Each time you return to our Sites, for example, persistent cookies allow us to identify you as a returning user so that you don’t have to re-enter information that you’ve already provided.
  * _Third-party cookies:_ AIP Publishing uses third-party cookies to enable our trusted partners to bring increased functionality to our Sites. For example, AIP Publishing has partnered with a service that enables the collection of usage data for our own marketing purposes. The information we obtain is used to offer you assistance, to help us make improvements to the website, or to send you special offers that relate to the content you’ve viewed.
  * _Web beacons:_ Web beacons, or single-pixel gifs, are a form of tracking technology that records user behavior. We use web beacons on our Sites and in emails we send to you to collect information such as whether you opened a web page or email, your IP address, the type of browser you used, etc. This information allows us to measure the effectiveness of our campaigns, target specific content only to those who are most interested, and improve our features and your overall user experience.
  * _Do Not Track:_ Some web browsers incorporate a Do Not Track (“ **DNT** ”) or similar feature that signals to digital services that a user does not want to have his/her online activity tracked. If a digital service that responds to a particular DNT signal receives the DNT signal, the browser can block that digital service from collecting certain information about that browser’s user. Not all browsers offer a DNT option and DNT signals are not yet uniform. For these reasons, we and many other digital service operators do not respond to DNT signals. For more information about DNT signals, visit [http://allaboutdnt.com](http://allaboutdnt.com/).  

**Online advertising**

We contract with third-party remarketing services, such as Google AdWords, to tailor advertising to our users. Using cookies, these services track what parts of our Sites you visited in order to serve you relevant ads on other websites you visit as you navigate across the Internet. This ensures you receive only content that is of interest to you. Please understand that if you disable cookies (as discussed below) to prevent such interest-based advertising, you will still see advertisements – but they will not be tailored to your interests.

**Your online choices**

You can control what types of cookies you wish to allow, delete, or disable through the settings in your browser. If you restrict cookies, however, you will not obtain the optimum benefit of the Sites’ functionality or be able to access all of the content. In addition, we participate in behavior-based advertising. This means that a third party uses technology (e.g., a cookie) to collect information about your use of our website so that they can provide advertising about products and services tailored to your interests. That advertising appears on either our websites or other websites. You can opt out of receiving advertising based upon your browsing behavior from some of the network advertising companies that deploy cookies on some of our websites by going to the Network Advertising Initiative website at [www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). You can also use the following links to opt-out of advertising based on the following tracking cookies:

  * If you would like to opt out of participating in Google AdWords Remarketing, please visit [Google’s Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous?sig=ACi0TCgggXMw1Cge50MmsKFyvvxUC4LNaXM3SkMr6MXe4VLgk-pQKsT1mecb5JvX04BLkiDfuJWpqGS6fgGAf5P3dg6o2BZAo3kH1Uo-AHbAI66fYo3ST0U&hl=en).
  * To prevent information from being collected by Google Analytics, you can install the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

**Your access, rectification, deletion, and opt-out rights**

AIP Publishing strives to make sure that the information we maintain is reliable, accurate, and up to date.

You can log into your account online to correct, update, or modify some of your information at any time. If you choose to delete your profile online, note that while your profile will become inactive, we continue to maintain personal information about you.

Upon request made to dataprivacy@aip.org, we will provide you with a copy of the Personal Information we hold about you to the extent required by law. You may also request that your Personal Information be updated, corrected, transferred, deleted, or that processing be restricted or discontinued by contacting us at that email address. If you contact us directly, we will take reasonable steps to confirm your identity before making any changes. Because Personal information — for example, your email address — is required to use the Sites, we retain certain Personal Information as long as your account is active. Please note that some information remains in our records even after you request its deletion, to the extent permitted by applicable laws. Additionally, there are limits to the amount of information we can practically provide. For example, we will limit access to Personal Information where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to an individual's privacy or where doing so would violate others' rights. 

If you wish to opt-out of having your Personal Information used for advertising or marketing purposes, or to remove your information from any list that might be shared with another organization consistent with this Privacy Policy, please send a request to [help@scitation.org](mailto:help@scitation.org). You may also unsubscribe from the marketing emails that you receive from us at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email or by sending your request to [help@scitation.org](mailto:help@scitation.org). If you unsubscribe from marketing communications, however, it will not limit our ability to send transactional communications to you regarding products or services you have requested.

**How we protect your Personal Information**

AIP Publishing takes reasonable and appropriate steps to protect and prevent unauthorized access to your Personal Information and to ensure the integrity of that information.

While AIP Publishing continually monitors the security status of its networks, it cannot guarantee that any transmission of data made over the Internet is totally secure. You have a responsibility as well to help protect the information you provide by keeping your account information confidential and not using unsecured or unencrypted networks.

**Data integrity and purpose limitation**

AIP Publishing limits the use of Personal Information to ways that are compatible and relevant to the purposes for which the Personal Information was collected or subsequently authorized or for which consent was obtained. We will take reasonable steps to ensure that Personal Information is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete, and current.

**Records retention**

AIP Publishing will retain your Personal Information as needed to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected. AIP Publishing will retain and use your Personal Information as necessary to comply with our business requirements and legal obligations, resolve disputes, protect our assets, and enforce our agreements.

**Your California rights**

If you are a California resident, you may request information (once per calendar year) regarding whether we disclosed your Personal Information to our affiliates and to third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [dataprivacy@aip.org](mailto:dataprivacy@aip.org) or write us:

CA Privacy Rights  
AIP Publishing LLC  
1305 Walt Whitman Road  
Suite 300  
Melville, NY 11747

**User submissions**

The Sites may offer users the opportunity to submit, publish, or share comments, reviews, and other content (“ **User Content** ”). Personal Information in User Content is viewable by others and can be used in unexpected ways. You submit your User Content at your own risk, and we will access and use your User Content consistent with this Privacy Policy. By communicating with any other user on the Sites, you explicitly “Opt In” to sharing such information, which includes Personal Information, with that user. To request removal of User Content, please contact us at [dataprivacy@aip.org](mailto:rights@aip.org). If we are unable to remove your User Content, we will let you know the reasons why.

**Links and third-party websites**

AIP Publishing Sites contain links to other websites, and other websites link to our Sites. Please be aware that AIP Publishing is not responsible for the privacy practices of third-party websites that we do not operate or control, and this Privacy Policy does not apply to the information collected by third parties through their websites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Sites and to read the privacy statements of each of the websites that you visit.

**Non-U.S. residents**

If you reside outside the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to us, including Personal Information, will be transferred to, collected, processed, and stored in the United States. Privacy and data protection laws differ from country to country, and the laws in the United States may offer less protection than the laws of your country. When you provide your information to us, you consent to the processing of your data in, and the transfer of your data to, the United States.

**Notification of changes**

The effective date of this Privacy Policy is set forth at the top of this page. Whenever possible, we will provide you with notice of any material changes to this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of the Sites after the effective date constitutes your acceptance of the amended Privacy Policy, which will replace and supersede all previous versions. We will send you periodic reminders to review this page for updates and notifications of changes posted to the Sites.

**Contact information**

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or how we use your information, please contact us at:

AIP Publishing LLC  
1305 Walt Whitman Road  
Suite 300  
Melville, NY 11747  
1-516-576-2200  

Legal entity that can receive items in Europe relating to AIP Publishing’s processing of information:

AIP Publishing  
c/o Bryan Cave Leighton Paisner LLP  
Attn: Erik Kahn - NY  
Adelaide House London Bridge  
London, United Kingdom  
EC4R 9HA

We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you are a data subject in the European Union, and you have an unresolved concern regarding your Personal Information that we have not addressed satisfactorily, you may also contact your local data protection authority.

If AIP Publishing needs or is required to contact you concerning any event that involves information about you, we will do so by email, telephone, or mail.
